lovoo.net 2019-06-27

# Legal Information LOVOO

**[Privacy Statement]**

This privacy statement is valid for the mobile app LOVOO, the site [www.lovoo.com](https://www.lovoo.com/imprint), and additional services offered by LOVOO GmbH which refer to this privacy statement.

tl;dr: To summarize, your privacy is important to LOVOO. Thus, we only use for full personal data for providing the LOVOO platform and product optimization. We will never share sensitive data like your name profile picture with third parties for advertising purposes. However, LOVOO is partially financed by advertising. To be able to show you adverts that are interesting to you we and/or our advertising partners use your published age and gender, your coarse location and device and network information to show you personalized adverts. We only share this data in pseudonymous form. Pseudonymous means, that we will not share the data together with your (user) name or your e-mail address or similar data, just with the Advertiser-ID. All our advertising partners are contractually and legally forbidden to join the transferred data with your real name and similar data.

If you want to object against the use of this data for advertising purposes, you can deactivate personalized advertising in the app setting under Privacy and in your device settings. On an apple device this can be done in the iOS preferences, under "Privacy" -- "Ads" and enabling the option "no ad tracking"; for a user owning an Android this can be achieved by opening the "Google Settings" (or first "Settings" and then "Google"), clicking on "Display" and ticking the option "Disable personalised ads. You can reset the IDFA or the Advertising ID at any time with these options.

**Introduction**

[LOVOO GmbH](https://www.lovoo.com/imprint), Prager Straße 10, 01069 Dresden, Germany ("LOVOO GmbH" or "we/us/our") owns the domain "[www.lovoo.com"](http://www.lovoo.com%22/) and all of its sub-pages ("LOVOO domain") where it provides mobile app LOVOO ("LOVOO app") available for download for various operating systems which is its principal means of running a platform for chatting with, getting to know and meeting other people ("LOVOO"). LOVOO GmbH is the data controller.

The service offering is based on the freemium model allowing a LOVOO user ("user" or "you") to use the LOVOO domain or run the LOVOO app to create a profile ("user profile"), upload images and exchange news etc. with other interested users and their user profiles for free. Users have access to various functions such as Chat, Live Radar, Match Game or Live-Video and many other LOVOO functions. Added to that, LOVOO offers a chargeable premium service for users who wish to gain access to further unique functions.

LOVOO's offering also lets you meet real people in your area and therefore classifies as a so-called dating service. Everybody aged 16 or older may register.

Collecting, processing and using your data is based on the provisions of the Federal Telemedia Act (TMG) and the data privacy laws, the latter particularly including the Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) and as of 25 May 2018 -- the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

This privacy statement explains how we will handle your personal data. Personal data is discrete information about private or objective conditions of a specific or identifiable natural person. Personal data includes, but is not limited to a person's name, birthday, phone number or the e-mail address and usage data such as the IP address. Another purpose of the privacy statement is to inform users about the data collected, saved and processed and how LOVOO GmbH ensures the protection and safety of personal data.

LOVOO GmbH does not insist on the use of real names. Users may specify a nickname instead of their real name. For some parts of LOVOO, e.g. if you receive money from LOVOO, you may be required to provide us with your name, your address and your citizenship for tax purposes. In this case we will inform you about this.

This privacy statement breaks down into the following sections:

##  Privacy Statement

    1. How is my data collected, processed and used when I download the LOVOO app?
        1.1. LOVOO app download
        1.2. Installation and access rights
    2. How does LOVOO collect, process and use my data if I just visit the LOVOO domain or the LOVOO app but do not create a user profile?
    3. How does LOVOO collect, process and use my data when I use the functions of the LOVOO app or the LOVOO domain after creating a user profile?
        3.1 Mandatory entries for creating a user profile
        3.2 Optional details
        3.3 Location data
        3.4 IP addresses
        3.5 Payment data
    4. How does LOVOO use my  data for advertising?
        4.1 How is my data used for LOVOO's  own advertising?
            4.1.1 Audiences
        4.2. How does LOVOO use my  data for personlized advertising?
            4.2.1. Which data is used for advertising and who is it given to?
            4.2.2. What is an advertiser ID and how is it used?
            4.2.3. Using location data
            4.2.4. legal basis for the use of personal data for advertising purposes
    5. Which cookies, tracking and analysis services providers does LOVOO use? How are social media and Like buttons integrated?
        5.1 Cookies and cookie policy
        5.2 Tracking, analysis service and security providers
        5.3 Social media links
        5.4 Embedded Like/Share buttons and social plug-ins
        5.5 Facebook-Connect
    6. How is data disclosed or forwarded?
        6.1 General notes on the forwarding of personal data
        6.2 Categories of data recipients
        6.3 Third countries
    7. How is data processed and used to prevent and fight fake-profiles, illegal activity and spam and to secure the integrity and stability of the LOVOO platform?
    8. How is data deleted and back-ups created?
    9. How does LOVOO ensure data integrity?
    10. User rights: consent and withdrawal of consent, information, correction, deletion, transfer
        10.1 Consent and withdrawal of consent
        10.2 Information, correction, deletion, transfer
    11. Changes to this privacy statement
    12. Privacy contact person and data protection officer

  1. How is my data collected, processed and used when I download the LOVOO app?

* * *

### 1.1. LOVOO app download

When you download the LOVOO app, the relevant data will be transferred to the app store operator concerned. Depending on the app store, the set of data may include the app store user's e-mail address or customer number, the time of download and a unique device ID, for example. However, LOVOO GmbH has no influence on and is not controller for this data processing. The privacy statements / settings of the relevant app store operator apply.

### 1.2. Installation and access rights

LOVOO needs various access pathways and data to ensure the technical operability of the LOVOO app and to provide the services you can run using the LOVOO app.

Depending on which operating system you use, the installer may already ask your permission to access specific functions and pieces of information. Such access rights cover the location, messages, mobile data and others.

The user preferences of some terminal devices allow user to manually withdraw some of these rights. If you do, please bear in mind that not granting these rights may render the LOVOO app partly or completely useless. Access rights will be checked before or after the installation, depending on your app version.

## 2\. How does LOVOO collect, process and use my data if I just visit the LOVOO domain or the LOVOO app but do not create a user profile?

Unless the user explicitly consents, LOVOO GmbH uses the personal data disclosed by the user or generated when using LOVOO without creating a user profile solely for performance of the contractual relationship and as is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by LOVOO GmbH use as described in this privacy statement.

Except for the data listed below, LOVOO does not collect any personal data if you simply visit the LOVOO domain (starting on a so-called landing or home page) or install the LOVOO app without creating a user profile.

The set of data contains:

  * IP address

  * name of requested website, file, date and time of request

  * data volume transferred

  * browser type and version

  * referrer URL (source URL) from which the user opened the page - requesting provider plus, the data below transferred by the user's terminal device if the user just installs the LOVOO app but neither registers nor creates a user profile:

  * push handle (for sending push messages)

  * location data (GPS location), if the user has granted such a permission on the device.

  * country code

  * language

  * device data, like manufacturer, device type, advertising-id, operating system and version of operating system.

This data is required to use the LOVOO domain or to install the LOVOO app as such or they are used for analysis for statistical purposes in order to optimise LOVOO. This data is used to prevent and fight fake-profiles, illegal activity and spam and to secure the integrity and stability of the LOVOO platform. For this purpose, we store the full data for up to 90 days.

Collecting, processing and using the location data is necessary for the user to run the so-called "location-based service" which provides registered users with suggestions tailored to the user's location. Sections 3.3 and 4.3 further explain the location data.

LOVOO also uses cookies (see section 5.1), analysis services and tracking providers (see section 5.2).

## 3\. How does LOVOO collect, process and use my data when I use the functions of the LOVOO app or the LOVOO domain after creating a user profile?

Unless the user explicitly consents, LOVOO GmbH uses the personal data disclosed by the user or generated when using LOVOO after creating a user profile solely for performance of the contractual relationship and as is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by LOVOO GmbH use as described in this privacy statement. Proper use of LOVOO to the full extent requires the user to create a user profile. This involves entering further personal data which LOVOO GmbH uses to provide the service agreed.

### 3.1. Data that you have provided to us

#### 3.1 Mandatory entries for creating a user profile

You must enter the following details to register and create a user profile:

  * email address

  * password

  * user name (nickname)

  * town

  * date of birth

  * sex

  * profile picture

We collect, process and use the data you enter so that you can use LOVOO. Among other things it helps us address and authenticate you, verify your age, personalise your profile, display matching user profiles and (in pseudonymous form) to show you ads (see section 4).

We delete this data when you delete your account. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) or Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

#### 3.1.2 Optional details

You may add many optional details to your user profile or enter search parameters. They particularly help LOVOO to select other user profiles by various criteria, suggest them to the user and display them in LOVOO. Additional details increase the probability of getting in touch with matching user profiles. However, these details are entirely optional, and the user can see, enter, modify or delete them in the Details section of the profile,

We collect, save and use the data you enter so that you can use LOVOO.

Whereas these optional details are visible as "public" information to other logged-in LOVOO users, the user owning the affected user profile can modify or delete them at any time via the Preferences section of the profile. This data may also be used for ads (see section 4 for information about advertising).

We delete this data when you delete your account. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) or Article 6 (1) f)of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

#### 3.1.3 Location data

LOVOO's offering includes so-called location-based services which display specific choices tailored to the user's location. A user can therefore be shown other users in the vicinity. To be able to provide these functions within the LOVOO app, LOVOO collects location data by means of GPS of the terminal device concerned as well as location data of nearby radio access nodes. Provided that the site survey is enabled, and permission is granted, the location will be periodically transferred to LOVOO GmbH and will be respectively processed and used.

Before collection of location data, users must allow the collection of location data. The location data is then processed in accordance with this privacy statement. If activated and granted, the location data is transferred to LOVOO GmbH at regular intervals to be processed and used.

Users can change this functionality at any time by displaying the Preferences of their terminal device's operating system at any time to either allow or disallow the collecting of location data.

Location data will also be used for advertising purposes, if the user has not objected to this in the app settings. (See section 4 for information about advertising).

We store location data unshortend for up to 14 days and shortened up to 90 days. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) or f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

### 3.2. Data that recieve by you usage of the LOVOO platform.

#### 3.2.1 IP addresses and network data

We keep the users' IP addresses and the associated network data (e.g. the country in which the IP address is registered) for safety and checking purposes. The aim is to prevent abuse of the service.

This data is used to prevent and fight fake-profiles, illegal activity and spam and to secure the integrity and stability of the LOVOO platform. For this purpose, we store the full data up to 90 days, after that until you delete your profile. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

For technical reasons the IP address will be transferred to advertising partner, see below at 4. LOVOO GmbH has selected its advertising partners with due diligence to ensure that your privacy is protected by contractual restrictions and the law.

#### 3.2.2 Device Data

When using the app or the website, we receive information about the devices used, such as the manufacturer, operating system, advertising ID.

The data is used to prevent and combat fake profiles, illegal actions and spam as well as the safeguarding of the integrity and stability of the LOVOO platform.

For this purpose, we store the collected data for up to 90 days in complete form and delete this data when you delete your user account. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Art. 6 I f) EU-DSGVO.

#### 3.2.3. Event data

When using the app or the platform, we receive information about your actions (a so-called event) in the app or on the platform, for example when you search for users by clicking data, a match is created or you send messages.

The data provided will be stored, processed and used by us for the purpose of using LOVOO. In particular, this serves LOVOO's function of selecting recommendations for other user profiles according to different criteria for the user and displaying them within LOVOO. This additional information increases the probability of coming into contact with suitable user profiles. This data is an important part of understanding which profiles are likely to be of interest to you and which profiles you would like us to display.

This data is also stored, processed and used to prevent and combat fake profiles, illegal actions and spam as well as to ensure the integrity and stability of the LOVOO platform.

We delete this data when you delete your user account.

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Art. 6. I lit. b) EU-DSGVO or Art. 6 I lit. f) EU-DSGVO.

### 3.3 Payment data

External payment service providers handle the transactions involved when a user does any In-App purchases via LOVOO, buys credits or subscribes to our chargeable premium service. LOVOO GmbH neither collects nor processes any payment data of shopping transactions. Instead, the payment service providers take care of entering and processing the payment data directly. All that LOVOO GmbH and the payment service providers do is to exchange technical data (e.g. the transaction ID) in order to validate the purchases. We save this data until your user account is deleted or beyond this point, until a time when the data is no longer subject to any tax-related, commercial or other statutory storage obligations. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

## 4\. How does LOVOO use my data for advertising?

We use data for adveristing in two regards:

  1. For our own advertising
  2. To display personalized advertising.

### 4.1 How is my data used for LOVOO's own advertising?

We display ads of our own to our users on our platform and also inform them by e-mail, e.g. about one-off campaigns, discounted package prices or similar offers. In order to be able to display suitable offers, we use information provided by the user (such as profile data) and information that we automatically receive through the use of our platform.

The user can object to the use for advertising purposes at any time by deactivating personalised advertising in the app settings under Privacy and or in his device settings or in the settings on the website.

The data transfer takes place exclusively as described under 6.

The legal basis for this processing is the legitimate interest of LOVOO according to Art. 6 I lit. f DSGVO.

#### 4.1.1. Audiences

We also use Audience offers from the following providers for our own advertising:

  * Snapchat Audiences

herinafter Audience Providers.

For this purpose, we transfer the e-mail addresses of selected users to the AudienceAprovider in a hashed form. This means that the email address [max.mustermann@lovoo.com](mailto:max.mustermann@lovoo.com) will be transmitted as 73b6756115fdeba0f42b63649d986d5c8d60932e890c0355308967c10f72d058. The Audience Provider will never receive the email address in plain text. This hashed email address is used by the Audience Provider to dsiplay our advertisements to people who have a similar profile as the user.

The user can object to this at any time by deactivating personalized advertising in the app settings under Privacy and or in his device settings or in the settings on the website.

The legal basis for this processing is the legitimate interest of LOVOO according to Art. 6 I lit. f DSGVO.

### 4.2. How does LOVOO use my data for personlized advertising?

LOVOO GmbH decided to run LOVOO as a freemium service which lets every user obtain a basic LOVOO version free of charge. Users of the free version will be shown ads. The ads shown in LOVOO contain our own advertising matters (such as the premium products of LOVOO) or content ordered by an advertising firm in so-called campaigns. Campaigns may be personalised to tailor them to specific user groups (e.g., ads for cosmetic products just for female or male users; skateboard ads only for persons under 25, etc.). Some ads shown in LOVOO are mediated by external service providers.

### 4.2.1. Which data is used for advertising and who is it given to?

LOVOO GmbH can use LOVOO to show third-party ads which may be tailored to the users' assumed specific interests (personalised ads) or targeted to certain user groups grouped by age, location or gender. The users can object to the use of its data in the privacy settings of the app. We and our advertising partners will only use non-sensitive data, that the you have published on LOVOO and information about your device and your connection. Under no circumstances will we share your name, your e-mail address, your profile picture or your exact location or similar data that allows a direct inference of your real person with our advertising partners.

Whenever such personalised ads are shown, the third-party provider whose ad is shown in LOVOO or whose services are used to show ads of other third parties the following pseudonymous data may be transferred (" **forwarded data** "):

  * advertiser ID

  * your published age and gender

  * your coarse location

  * technical data of the terminal device

  * LOVOO usage data

  * data of ads shown

Forwarded data is disclosed to the following categories of recipients for the purposes explained:

  * ad network operators, including [MoPub](https://www.mopub.com/legal/privacy/) and its [Partners](https://www.mopub.com/legal/partners) and [Teads](https://www.teads.tv/privacy-policy/) and [Smaato](https://www.smaato.com/privacy/)

  * tracking services operators

  * affiliate networks

  * customer relationship services operators

  * other sales & marketing partners

**You can object to this processing for the future at any time by going to the privacy settings of the LOVOO app or the device settings. You can also reset your Advertising ID in your device settings. In that case a new Advertising ID is created which will not be joined with older data. With this you can ensure, that you will not see any ads based on the forwarded data before you have objected to the transfer.**

All our partners are obligated to process forwarded data only on accordance with the high data protection principles of the European Union and only for advertising purposes. This means, that all partners are obligated no not identify the real user / or remove the Pseudonymity of the data.

The recipients of forwarded data are sometimes seated outside of the European Union. LOVOO GmbH transfers forwarded data only to third countries, if the data protection level of the third country is adequate or the recipients has provided appropriate safeguards.

Forwarded data is transferred to the following countries:

  * USA (EU-US-Privacy-Shield and EU Standard Contract Clause)

  * Israel (Adequacy decision of the European Union)

The Privacy Shield treaty, the Adequacy decision and the EU Standard Contract Clause can be reviewed at the website of the EU commission (<https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>)

### 4.2.2. What is an advertiser ID and how is it used?

For tracking and advertising, the LOVOO app uses the so-called advertiser ID, i.e. the "Advertiser Identifier" (IDFA) for offerings of Apple Inc. and the "Android Advertiser ID" (advertiser ID) for offerings of Google. Inc. (jointly the " **advertiser ID(s)** "). These advertiser IDs are unique non-permanent numbers identifying a specific terminal device. They are provided by iOS for offerings of Apple Inc. or by Android for offerings of Google Inc. As opposed to vendor advertiser IDs (generated by latest-generation operating systems and identical for the apps of just one provider), the advertiser ID is the same as the one transferred to other companies when running their apps. The user can deactivate the generation of the Advertiser-ID. On an apple device this can be done in the iOS preferences, under "Privacy" -- "Ads" by enabling the option "no ad tracking"; for a user owning an Android this can be achieved by opening the "Google Settings" (or first "Settings" and then "Google"), clicking on "Display" and ticking the option "Disable personalised ads. The Advertiser ID is pseudonymous and LOVOO GmbH will not be joined with other user data to identify him for advertising purposes.

The Advertiser ID will be used by LOVOO GmbH and our advertising partner as described above to show you personalized advertising and to analyse this advertising. You can always object to this pseudonymous use by disabling the Advertiser ID as described above or objecting in the privacy settings of our app.

For further details and Apple Inc.'s privacy policy visit: <https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/>

For further details and Google Inc.'s privacy policy visit: <https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/>

### 4.2.3. Using location data

Apart from collecting the location data by running GPS Location (see section 3.3) to enable the location-based services, LOVOO GmbH collects and uses other location data to show the user ads in LOVOO tailored to the user's location and profile. LOVOO GmbH will never forward the exact location to our advertising partners. To protect your privacy all provided location data is coarse by around 2 km. To our knowledge with this data the identification of an individual is not or only with an unreasonable and illegal measures possible.

**For users that are sensitive to privacy question, we offer a separate option in the apps privacy settings to object of the use of location data for the future.**

### 4.2.4. legal basis for the use of personal data for advertising purposes

LOVOO GmbH bases the processing of sharing of the above data on the performance of the contract with you (Article 6 (1) b) GDPR in connection with Nr. 11.2. of our Terms of Service), your consent (Article 6 (1) a) GDPR) and the legitimate interests pursued by us (Article 6 (1) f) GDPR).

We offer our users a service under the Freemium model, which means, that certain parts of LOVOO are free to use. In Exchange for using the LOVOO platform without charge, LOVOO GmbH displays personalized advertisings and process and shares pseudonymous data as specified above.

Pre-requirement for all data transfer is that the recipient ensures by contractual, legal, technical and organizational measure that the data processing is always in compliance with privacy law.

The users consents to the data use and transfer to the recpients above when using the free version of the app.

We have decided to only share data, which -- even in the event of an unlawful disclosure or by hacking of our partners -- is not sensitive for individual users. We thus only share data in pseudonymous form and only data that the user has made public or is -- by its nature -- not sensitive like device and network data.

LOVOO will only pass on data that has been voluntarily made public on the LOVOO platform by the user and therefore shows a low level of sensitivity to the user and device or connection data which, due to their very nature, have are not sensitive.

### 5.1 Cookies and cookie policy

The LOVOO domain uses cookies to make using the LOVOO domain a very comfortable experience. Cookies are small text files temporarily stored locally by the Internet browser (so-called session cookies) or on the hard disk of either the mobile device or the computer (so-called permanent cookies). You can set your browser application to refusing to accept cookies or to asking you before a cookie is accepted. If cookies are accepted, the user is assigned an alias ID. A cookie neither runs programs on the user's terminal device nor does it transfer viruses. Session cookies are temporarily stored and deleted when you end your browser session.

LOVOO GmbH also uses cookies to increase the safety of the LOVOO domain, e.g. to authenticate a user during a session in order to avoid cross-site scripting or to prevent phishing and scamming.

In the name of LOVOO GmbH, tracking/analysis services providers (for details see section 5.2 Tracking and analysis services providers) upload cookies to a user's device in order to capture that user's usage data. This set of data includes details collected while the user is browsing the pages of the LOVOO or other domain or clicking on ad banners. These cookies are used to display tailored ads, optimise advertising campaign reports and to avoid repeatedly showing the same ads.

Users have the option to influence the usage of cookies, most browsers provide a setup option for restricting or completely prohibiting the saving of cookies. Please note, though, that disabling the use of cookies may limit the use and convenience of LOVOO.

For further details, please read our Cookie Policy at <https://lovoo.com/legal/cookies>.

### 5.2 Tracking, analysis service and security providers

By analysing what its visitors do, LOVOO optimises its services and how they are offered. To this end, LOVOO GmbH deploys methods able to analyse visits to the LOVOO domain or the LOVOO app. We also use tracking tools provided by third parties in order to analyse the reach of various advertising and marketing campaigns. Running third-party tools may involve the transfer of personal data.

While data processing mainly helps to troubleshoot LOVOO, it is also important for optimising LOVOO and adapting it to its users' needs. Web analysis provides further details which are useful for LOVOO GmbH to obtain key facts about the number of visitors and how they distribute over time, about favourite content and the time users spend on our site. It may sometimes be possible or necessary to verify whether a user profile was created in response to a specific promotional activity. The data is further used for fraud and spam prevention. To actually analyse the user data, it is transferred to various third-party providers.

LOVOO currently uses the following analysis and tracking services providers:

**Crashlytics (Fabric)**

The LOVOO app runs the analysis tool "Crashlytics" (Fabric) supplied by Crashlytics, 1 Kendall Square, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA (" **Crashlytics** "). This analysis utility uses the users' IP addresses albeit always after making them anonymous. It is therefore impossible to trade an address back to a real person. Crashlytics provides LOVOO GmbH with real-time analyses of system crashes which is a great help in maintaining and improving the LOVOO app or LOVOO domain. Details transferred are one user ID, the clicks as well as technical device data needed to analyse the error.

For further data protection details, read the privacy policy of Crashlytics: <http://try.crashlytics.com/terms/>

The main purpose of tracking and the analysis of user behaviour that this entails is to fulfil our contractual obligations, especially to reduce crashes, bugs and to improve our product. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

**Google Analytics**

LOVOO runs " **Google Analytics** " supplied by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (" **Google** "). LOVOO GmbH wishes to make you aware of the fact that, in LOVOO, Google Analytics has been extended by IP masking function "_gat._anonymizeIp" which ensures that IP addresses are made anonymous first.

_Please note the following details regarding the use of Google Analytics:_

Google Analytics uses cookies to enable the analysis of how LOVOO is used. As a rule, the cookie transfers the details of how you use LOVOO to a Google server in the US and stores them there. First of all, and provided that IP anonymisation is enabled, however, Google shortens your IP address used within the EU Member States or within other members of the Treaty on the European Economic Area. In the name of LOVOO GmbH, Google will use these details to analyse how you use our service, to compile activity reports and to provide the operator with other services linked to your use of LOVOO.

We only use Google Analytics with the user's consent, by allowing us to set the necessary cookies. We save this data for 26 months. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) a) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

**Adjust**

LOVOO uses "adjust", an app usage analysis tool supplied by adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 37 a in 10405 Berlin, Germany. When installing the LOVOO app, adjust will save installation and event data of your iOS or Android app. This helps us understand how our users are interacting with the LOVOO app. It also allows us to analyse and improve our mobile advertising campaigns. Analysis by adjust is based on the IDFA or the Advertiser ID as well as your anonymous IP and MAC address. This unilaterally anonymous data disallows to identify you or your mobile device. In case you wish to disable tracking by adjust, please go to [www.adjust.com/opt-out](http://www.adjust.com/opt-out).

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

The LOVOO domain contains links to LOVOO GmbH accounts with the following social networks: Instagram, YouTube, Pinterest, Twitter, Facebook and Google+. After clicking on the embedded picture, you will be taken to the associated Instagram, YouTube, Pinterest, Twitter, Facebook or Google+ page. That is to say that user data will not be transferred to the provider until you click on a link. The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) a) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

Provided that you and your user profile are logged in to the social destination network at the time, your click on the button will be associated with your visit to LOVOO.

If you do not wish the social media to collect data via the LOVOO domain, we recommend that you log off your social network before you visit the LOVOO domain. But even so, one or several cookies with an ID will be uploaded when you click on the button and run LOVOO. This function may therefore collect data and create a profile which may then be traced back to a specific natural person. If you do not wish this to happen, just visit the LOVOO domain and click on the correct option to disable the function. Or you can set your browser to never accepting any cookies; please note that this may restrict the functionality of LOVOO.

For details on how these sites handle personal data, please read the privacy policies of the relevant providers.

**Facebook**

Visit <https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/> to read Facebook's privacy policy (operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA).

**Twitter**

Visit <https://twitter.com/privacy> to read Twitter's privacy policy (operated by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA).

**Instagram**

Visit [https://www.instagram.com](https://www.instagram.com/) or <https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388> to read Instagram's privacy policy (operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA).

**Google+ / YouTube**

Visit <https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy/> to read Google's / YouTube's privacy policy (both operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA).

**Pinterest**

Visit <https://about.pinterest.com/de/privacy-policy> to read Pinterest's privacy policy (operated by Pinterest Inc., 808 Brannan Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA).

You will also find that social plug-ins of Facebook (operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA) and Twitter (operated by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom Street, Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA) are embedded in the LOVOO domain but disabled at first.

Clicking on "Like us on facebook" or "Follow us on twitter" enables the social plug-in of Facebook or Twitter. Only then will your user data be transferred to the Facebook or Twitter provider. With another click to "like" or "follow" the account of LOVOO GmbH, the service will then notify you of all activities of LOVOO GmbH's account with Facebook or Twitter. LOVOO GmbH has no say in how these networks collect, process and use your data.

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) a) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

If you do not wish the social media to collect data via the LOVOO domain, we recommend that you log off your social network before you visit the LOVOO domain. But even so, one or several cookies with an ID will be uploaded when you click on the button and run LOVOO. This function may therefore collect data and create a profile which may then be traced back to a specific natural person. If you do not wish this to happen, just visit the LOVOO domain and click on the correct option to disable the function. Or you can set your browser to never accepting any cookies; please note that this may restrict the functionality of LOVOO.

**Facebook**

The LOVOO domain uses the social plug-in of Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA needed for the social network at facebook.com.

Visit <https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/> to read Facebook's privacy policy.

**Twitter**

The LOVOO domain uses the social plug-in of Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA for the social network at twitter.com.

Visit <https://twitter.com/privacy> to read Twitter's privacy policy.

### 5.5 Facebook-Connect

LOVOO GmbH allows you to run Facebook-Connect to log in to LOVOO. To log in, you will be forwarded to the Facebook page (operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA) where you use your user data to log in if not logged in yet. A single click then links your Facebook profile to your LOVOO user profile. This link then automatically provides LOVOO GmbH with your Facebook data, i.e. your e-mail address and other details stored with your public Facebook profile. Your public Facebook profile shows all data you have made publicly known via Facebook. A public Facebook profile normally consists of the following details: your name, profile picture, sex, language, country, age bracket, Facebook ID, friends, likes and your relationship status.

Of these details provided by Facebook, LOVOO GmbH just uses your e-mail address, Facebook ID, profile picture, likes and your date of birth. These details go into your user profile. For further information about Facebook-Connect and its privacy settings please visit <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php> and read Facebook's privacy rules and terms of use.

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) a) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

## 6\. How is data disclosed or forwarded?

LOVOO GmbH does not forward the personal data of its users to third parties, unless the user explicitly agrees, or such forwarding is required or permitted by law.

### General notes on the forwarding of personal data

**User and other data**

LOVOO GmbH may transfer customer data to the following third parties if such data concern the execution of the contract:

  * External service providers and their agents. LOVOO GmbH may order external companies or persons to process customer data.

  * Affiliated companies as processor. LOVOO GmbH may instruct affiliated companies to process customer data.

  * Affiliated companies as controller. LOVOO GmbH may transfer customer data to other members of the company group for internal administrative purposes. Legal basis for such a transfer is Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR with recital nr. 48 GDPR.

**Other disclosures**

LOVOO GmbH may forward or disclose customer data as follows:

  * Subject to changes to its organisation. In conjunction with mergers, acquisitions, bankruptcy or liquidation proceedings, restructuring measures, divestment of some of all of LOVOO GmbH's assets, funding procedures, acquisition of some or all of our business, similar transactions or proceedings or steps having regard to such activities (e.g. due diligence investigations).

  * Subject to statutory regulations. In order to comply with statutory regulations or authority constraints and in response to legitimate inquiries, court orders and legal procedures.

  * Subject to enforcing LOVOO GmbH's rights, to preventing fraud and to ensuring safety. To protect and defend the rights, property and/or safety of LOVOO GmbH or third parties, including the enforcement of contracts and directives and in support of investigating and preventing cases of fraud.

  * LOVOO GmbH may use aggregate data or data not containing any personally identifiable facts for any purpose. For business or analysis purposes LOVOO GmbH may thus forward such aggregate data or data not containing any personally identifiable facts to partners or others by publishing the number of messages sent via LOVOO on a specific day, for example.

  * We may share customer data in pseudonymous form with our advertising partners, see section 4.

  * We may share pseudonymous data with tracking, analysis service and security providers, see section 5.2

### 6.2 Categories of data recipients

LOVOO GmbH gives third parties access to your personal data only if this is necessary for our own business purpose (especially performance of contract), with your consent, if is covered by our own legitimate interest, or when we are obliged to on legal grounds, by court order, or at the request of another official authority.

We work together with external service providers for our data processing. This is usually carried out on an order processing basis, whereby we remain responsible for data processing. We review each of these service providers beforehand with regard to the measures they have undertaken to ensure data protection and data security, thereby safeguarding the contractual provisions as stipulated by law for the protection of the personal data.

Currently we the following categories of recipients receive data from us:

  * Public authorities and courts

  * Technical service providers

  * Hosting providers

  * E-mail sending providers

  * E-mail marketing providers

  * customer support services (e.g. Zendesk)

  * advertising and sales partners (see section 4.1)

  * Cooperation partners

  * Other platform providers for the purpose of "Social Plugins"

  * analysis and tracking services (see section 5.2)

  * other members of the company group

Depending on which services are provided, LOVOO GmbH may also ask affiliated companies to act as data processing services provider for providing some or all of the services offered its customers.

### 6.3. Third countries

The recipients of forwarded data are sometimes seated outside of the European Union. LOVOO GmbH transfers forwarded data only to third countries, if the data protection level of the third country is adequate or the recipients has provided appropriate safeguards.

Forwarded data is transferred to the following countries:

  * USA (EU-US-Privacy-Shield and EU Standard Contract Clause)

  * Israel (Adequacy decision of the European Union)

  * India (EU Standard Contract Clause)

The Privacy Shield treaty, the Adequacy decision and the EU Standard Contract Clause can be reviewed at the website of the EU commission (<https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection_en>)

## 7\. How is data processed and used to prevent and fight fake-profiles, illegal activity and spam and to secure the integrity and stability of the LOVOO platform?

Personal data is used as described below used to prevent and fight fake-profiles, illegal activity and spam and to secure the integrity and stability of the LOVOO platform.

  * IP and email addresses are saved to detect spam & scam for as long as the user is active.

  * Messages are automatically checked for specific keywords but not saved for this purpose.

  * Personal data such as an active user's sex, age and location is saved and pooled with other non-personal data in order to detect any abnormalities.

  * Whereas previous phone numbers are saved to check suspicious profiles sent by SMS, such phone numbers cannot be associated with the verified user.

**Google reCaptcha**

We use Google's reCaptcha service to protect the LOVOO platform. The reCaptcha is used to detect if the Input has been made by a human or by fraudulent, automated machines. For this purpose, your IP address and other data required by the Google Service is transferred to Google.

For this service Google's privacy statement applies: <https://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/>.

**CloudFlare**

LOVOO GmbH uses technology of CloudFlare Inc, Inc 665 3rd St. 200, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA to protect the LOVOO platform and increase the security and stability of the platform. For this purpose, CloudFlare and/or LOVOO will -- among others - set cookies on your device, analyse your device and network data to detect and differentiate legitimate LOVOO users from hackers, SPAM, etc. Cloudflare processes this data only on behalf of LOVOO and not for their own purpose. Additional information for this can be found at: <https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy>.

**Legal basis**

The legal basis for this processing is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). LOVOO GmbH has a legitimate interest in keeping the LOVOO platform stable and free of SPAM, illegal activity and fake-profiles.

## 8\. How is data deleted and back-ups created?

Deleting a user profile (attention: not by deleting the LOVOO app!) or notifying us accordingly deletes all of that user's data. Apart from that, users can remove profile details themselves or ask us to do so at any time.

Exempt of such a deletion is data, that we have to retain by statutory storage obligations, for winding up the contract and for performance of contract with other users. For example, we will not promptly delete the following data:

  * Payment data and data regarding reward claims, which we have to retain for tax-related, commercial or other statutory storage obligations.

  * Data, which you have shared with other users in chats, like messages or pictures (see below)

**When do we delete data, that you have shared with other users?**

We delete data which is accessible in your public profile, like profile pictures, stream pictures and profile data, promptly as specified above.

We can't delete data that you have shared non-publicly with other users without infringing the rights of this other user. Thus, we can delete chat data only after both users have delete their profile.

**How long will it take to delete the data?**

Such details will be immediately removed from the productive databases and, thus from the LOVOO interface; however, it may take up to 14 days until the data is removed from all of LOVOO's server layers, cache memories and back-up databases.

If deletion is not possible, we will anonymize the data or restrict the processing.

**In case certain facts lead to the suspicion that a user profile uses LOVOO illegally or contrary to the contract with us, we reserve the right to check and perhaps save profile files before deleting them. This is to protect the users of LOVOO GmbH's offerings.**

Irrespective of data deleted because of user-deleted profiles, LOVOO automatically and periodically deletes historical data no longer needed to perform the contract (e.g. historical location details and IP data).

In order to protect its datasets, LOVOO GmbH creates so-called back-up copies which are overwritten and, thus, deleted for good after 14 days. Deletion also affects log files that may be contained in these back-ups. Log files will also be deleted when a user profile is completely deleted.

## 9\. How does LOVOO ensure data integrity?

The trust of its users and protecting their data is of great importance to LOVOO GmbH. To prevent unauthorised access to or disclosure of user data and to ensure the integrity and appropriate use of the data, LOVOO GmbH has appropriate physical, technical and administrative procedures in place to protect the information collected by LOVOO GmbH.

To provide highest-level protection of the user data, the offerings of the LOVOO domain or LOVOO app rely on a secure SSL connection that allows the transfer of nothing but encrypted data.

## 10\. User rights: consent and withdrawal of consent, information, correction, deletion, transfer

### 10.1 Consent and withdrawal of consent

When registering with LOVOO, users agree to collecting, saving and processing their personal data subject to this Privacy Statement and our General Terms and Conditions. Users will have to explicitly consent to this procedure when they create their user profile. LOVOO GmbH logs both the granting of the consent and the entire process of user profile creation.

Users can withdraw their consent at any time and with future effect. Methods of doing so is by deleting their user profile (not the LOVOO app), going to the specified user profile places in the LOVOO app or LOVOO domain or by sending us an email, fax or letter to:

LETTER: LOVOO GmbH, Prager Str. 10, 01069 Dresden, Germany

FAX: +49 351 41887779

EMAIL: [datenschutz@lovoo.com](mailto:datenschutz@lovoo.com)

### 10.2 Information, correction, deletion, transfer

Subject to the applicable laws, users have a right to being informed about their personal data stored and a right to correcting, deleting and/or transferring such data, if so.

To exercise these rights, users may send an email to [datenschutz@lovoo.com](mailto:datenschutz@lovoo.com).

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

## 11\. Changes to this privacy statement

LOVOO GmbH will update this privacy statement as necessary. Using the user data is subject to the most recent version available for download at <https://www.lovoo.com/legal/privacy>. An email will be sent to the email address stored with the user profile to inform users about major changes to this statement (e.g. changes to the user rights, new functions, new contact persons etc.). By continued access to and use of LOVOO after such changes have taken effect, users declare their consent to being legally bound to the revised privacy statement.

If you have questions concerning the collection, processing or use of your personal data, if you wish to be informed, to correct, bar or delete any data or to withdraw a previous consent, please do one of the following: delete your user profile (not the LOVOO app) or go to the specified user profile places in the LOVOO app or LOVOO domain and modify your user profile there

or send us an email, fax or letter to:

LOVOO GmbH

Prager Str. 10, 01069 Dresden, Germany

FAX: +49 351 41887779

EMAIL: [datenschutz@lovoo.com](mailto:datenschutz@lovoo.com)

### Data Protection Officer

ePrivacy GmbH

Managing Director Prof. Dr. Christoph Bauer

Große Bleichen 21

20354 Hamburg

E-MAIL: [datenschutz@lovoo.com](mailto:datenschutz@lovoo.com)
